Guide to the Ernest Ropiequet Hilgard Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ernest Ropiequet Hilgard papers
1942-2000
SC0210
Hilgard, Ernest R. (Ernest Ropiequet), 1904-2001
100 Linear feet
Papers document his professional career as researcher (focusing on hypnosis) and professor at Stanford University; included are correspondence, research files, articles and papers, lectures, reprints, course materials, records from Professor Hilgard's extensive Stanford committee activities, and his memoirs (1991). Collection includes a small number of videos, audio tapes, and photographs.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Professor Ernest Hilgard, 1979, 1995, and 2000.
Information about Access
Some of the hypnosis study materials received in 2000 are restricted pending review.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of Psychology and Education at Stanford, since 1933; Dean of Graduate Division, 1951-1955.
Description of the Collection
Papers document his professional career as researcher (focusing on hypnosis) and professor at Stanford University; included are correspondence, research files, articles and papers, lectures, reprints, course materials, records from Professor Hilgard's extensive Stanford committee activities, and his memoirs (1991). Collection includes a small number of videos, audio tapes, and photographs.
Access Terms
Hilgard, Ernest R. (Ernest Ropiequet), 1904-2001; Stanford University. Department of Psychology. Faculty.; Faculty; Hypnotism.; Psychology--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-1995-093
  - Memoirs of Ernest R. Hilgard, 1991 (Box 1)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2000-164
  - JRH General Misc. 1982/83 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - JRH Personal Data 1982/83 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Hypnosis in the Treatment of Pain & Anxiety. Young Patients w/Cancer (Corres./Misc) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - I – Miscellaneous 1983 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - 1984 IJCEH Reviews – ORNE (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - 1983 IJECH Reviews – ORNE (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - ISH: 9th International Congress of Hypnosis & Psychosomatic Medicine – Glasgow August 1982 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - International Society of Hypnosis 1982-83 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - K – Miscellaneous 1983 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Kaufmann, William Inc. 1982-83 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - L – Miscellaneous 1983 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Leary, David E. 1982-83 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - M – Miscellaneous 1983 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Mc, Mac – Miscellaneous 1983 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - ERH Stephen Westley Mosher Case Grievance Committee, etc. 1983 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - National Academy of Education 1982-83 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - National Academy of Education: Academy Notes (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - National Academy of Sciences 1982/83 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - National Science Foundation 1982-83 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - O – Miscellaneous 1983 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - 1982-83 Prentice-Hall Publishers (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - R – Miscellaneous 1983 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - S – Miscellaneous 1983 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - SCEH Nominations/Awards 1983 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - SCEH Meeting – Boston 1983 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - SCEH – General (1982/83) (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - ERH Lecture to the So Cal Society of Clinical Hypnosis 8/24/83 in LA (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Stanford University – Miscellaneous 1982-83 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Supplies – General 1982/83 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - T – Miscellaneous 1983 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - W – Miscellaneous 1983 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Watkins, John G. (continuing file) (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - WPA Meeting – April 1983 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Wichita Engagement (April 1983) (Tinterow) (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Wiley Encyclopedia of Psychology (Corsini) 1982/83 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - X Y Z – Miscellaneous 1983 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - A – Miscellaneous 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - American Philosophical Society 1983-85 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - APA General/Miscellaneous 1984 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Los Angeles APA Meeting 1985 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - APA Oral History Advisory Group 1985 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - B – Miscellaneous 1984 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - B – Miscellaneous 1985 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Balthazard, Claude G. 1985 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Barabasz, Arreed, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Bowers, K.S. 1984-85 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Braun, Bennett G., M.D. 1984 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - C – Miscellaneous 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (G. Lindzey) 1984 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Crawford, Helen J. 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - G – Miscellaneous 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - G – Miscellaneous 1985 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - D – Miscellaneous 1983/84 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - E – Miscellaneous 1984 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Fromm, Erika 1983-84 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Greissman, Judith (Basic Books) 1982/83 84/85 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - H – Miscellaneous 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Continuing File – 1984-1985 Harcourt Brace Jovanovich Publishers History of Psychology Book – ERH (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - ERH Univ. of Illinois 4/30-5/2/85 Early Years of Intelligence Measmt. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - ERH Guilford Press Chapter Re Hypnosis & Memory 1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Milton Erickson as Playwright & Dir. Toronto – August 1985 10th Internat'l Congress ISH – ERH – (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Declinations of Invites to Conf. Talks, Editorships – ERH 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - ERH Recommendations, References 1985 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - ERH Paper Educational Psychol. (J. Glover) Plenum Press 1983-84 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - 1979-1984 Harcourt Brace Jovanovich Publishers History of Psychology Book – ERH (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Letters of Recommendation/Promotion 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - JRH Channing House 1982/85 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - I – Miscellaneous 1984-85 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - 1985 – ISH: International Congress – Toronto (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Residues from Toronto (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - IJECH Reviews ORNE 1985 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - ISH International Society of Hypnosis – P. Bloom, M.D., Secty-Treas 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Jana (India) 1983-84 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Josephson, Trevor 1984 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - American Journal of Psychology – General/Obituaries 1982-1985 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - 1984 British J. of Exper. & Clin. Hypnosis. Brian J. Fellows, Editor 1985 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Journal of Mental Imagery Akhter Ashen, Editor 1982-1985 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Journal Psychology Today (John Wilkes, UC-Santa Cruz) 1985 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Journals (General) 1985 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Psychological Reports Carol H. Ammons, Editor (Journal) 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - K – Miscellaneous 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - 1982-83-85 Kihlstrom, John F. (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - L – Miscellaneous 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Leary, David 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - M – Miscellaneous 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Mc, Mac – Miscellaneous 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - N – Miscellaneous 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - National Academy of Education 1985 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - National Academy of Sciences April '84 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - National Academy of Sciences 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Orne, Martin (Unit for Exper. Psychiatry) Panel of Sci. Advisors – ERH 1984/85 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - P – Miscellaneous 1983/84 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Prentice-Hall, Inc. 1984 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - P – Miscellaneous 1985 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Business & Professional Code – Psychologists – 1985 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - R – Miscellaneous 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Recommendations 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Society of Experimental Psychologists 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - SCEH Society for Clinical and Experimental Hypnosis Mtg-San Antonio 1984 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Sokal, Michael 1984-85 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - T – Miscellaneous 1985 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Thompson (something unreadable) Hist of Physiol. Psych. 1985 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - V – Miscellaneous 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - W – Miscellaneous 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - John Wiley & Sons 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - X Y Z – Miscellaneous 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - A – Miscellaneous 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - APA Meeting – Washington, D.C. 1986-Aug (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - American Psychologist Obituaries 1982-1986 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - American Psychologist Obituaries 1987 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - APA Convention – New York 1987 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - APA (General-Miscellaneous) 1986-87 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - APA Oral History Interviews (John C. Flanagan) 1987 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - APA Oral History Interviews Hilgard/Sears, Thurstone 1987 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - APA Oral History Interviews: M. Brewster Smith, Ph.D. 1987 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - APA Oral History Advisory Group 1986 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - APA Task Force on Centennial 1986-88 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - American Scientist 1986 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - The American Society of Clinical Hypnosis (L.L. Dubin, Chairman) 30th Ann. Mtg. Chicago, 3/16-18/88 1988 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Athavale, Dr. J.B. The Indian Society for Clinical Hypnosis & Research 1985 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Australian Society of Hypnosis Michael Boyd, Federal Secretary 1983-1986 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - B - Miscellaneous 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Book Expenses 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - C – Miscellaneous 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Capshew, James H. (1985-1986) (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Carrier Foundation Pettinati, Helen 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Computers 1986 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Contemporary Psychology 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Crawford, Helen 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - 4th European Congress of Hypnosis 1987 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - F – Miscellaneous 1984-1986 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Gettysburg College Talk Prof. S. Mudd Sept. 1986 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Hypnosis and Pain (Rev.) 1986 Raven Press (Sternbach) (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Invitation to Speak 9/24/86 NY State University-Albany, NY (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Invitations to Speak: Interviews, Meetings (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Dedication Speech UNH May 1986 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - SCEH Symposium Chicago Sept. 1986 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Milton Erickson as Playwright and Director IJCEH Symposium October 1987 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - General-Miscellaneous 1983-1986 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Lawrence Erlbaum Associates, Incl, Publ. Foreword for Brown/Fromm book 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Honorary Degree Recipient Colgate University May 22-24, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Lectures, Talks, Interviews, 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Research Advances in Hypnosis: Issues & Methods. IJCEH (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Review-Behavior & Logical Positivism ISIS, U of Penna. 1987 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - "Brown Bag Tours" UC-SF (J. W. Crawford) May 27, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Northwestern Honorary Degree 20 June, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Ad Hoc Committee – Review of Neurosciences Ph.D. Program 1987 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - The American Society of Clinical Hypnosis Des Plaines, IL (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Plenum Press Perspectives on Educ. Psychol. 1986-1987 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Archives – History of American Psychology (Akron, O.) (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Recommendations, References 986=1987 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Inst. For Scientific Info "Hypnotic Susc." Referenced in Citation Classics E. Garfield, Pres. 1987 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - IJCEH Reviews 1986 (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - IJCEH Reviews 1987 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Inventory of Books Donated to SU Library; Inv. Of books in Room 206, left side 1986 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - ISH: International Society of Hypnosis – Peter Bloom, Secretary-Treasurer 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - International Society of Hypnosis – Peter Bloom, Secretary-Treasurer 1987 (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - K – Miscellaneous 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - William Kaufman (Annual Reviews, Inc.) 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Leary, David 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - McNemar, Quinn (Memoriam) 1986 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - M – Miscellaneous 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - N – Miscellaneous 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - National Academy of Sciences 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Orne, Martin T. (Unit for Experimental Psychiatry) 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Oshins, Eddie (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - P – Miscellaneous 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - PSY-SR Legislative Task Force (Psychologists for Social Responsibility) 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - R – Miscellaneous 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Round Table Discussion UC Berkeley – K. Craik 5-7-87 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - S – Miscellaneous 1984-1986 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - S – Miscellaneous 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Scott, Foresman (General Editorship-ERH) 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Social Science Quotations (re Clark Hull) R.K. Merton/D. Sills (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Soc. For Clin. & Exper. Hypnosis Los Angeles Oct. 26-31 1987 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues (, D. W. Osgood) 1986 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Tsuchimochi, Gary (Educ. In Japan-1946 Study) 1987 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Video, Recording Tapes, & Microfilms (on file w/ B. Miner, or in Room 206) 1987 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Zeltzer, Lonnie, M. D. 1983-1986 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - A – Miscellaneous 1988 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - American Academy of Sciences 1984-1988 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - American Philosophical Society 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - American Psychological Assoc. 1988 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - APA Oral History Advisory Group 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - APA Oral History Interview M. Brewster Smith, Ph.D. 1989 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - APA Oral History Interview K. B. Little 1988 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - APA Oral History Interview M. S. Pallak 1988 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - APA Oral History Interviews 1988 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - APA/ICP Journal Donation Program 1988 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - B – Miscellaneous 1988 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Bolton, ED On My Voices Paper on his experience 1988 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Bowers, K. S. 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Video Interview Transcription K. Bowers – July 1984 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Brigham Young University Colloquial Speaker (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Bruner, Jerome C. 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Ctr. For Advanced Study of the Behavioral Sciences (Hilgard/Tyler) (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Citations Classics – ISI 1988 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - D – Miscellaneous 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Exper. Psychology Colloqium-A. Kawamoto (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Profile: in Milton H. Ericson Newsletter (M. Yapko, Ed.) 1988 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - F – Miscellaneous 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - G – Miscellaneous 1986-1988 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Dr. Gheorghiu 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Foreword to Gheorgiu, et. Al. Suggestibility: Theory and Research Springer-Verlag 1988 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Guilford Publications, Inc. (Chapt. in Pettinati book, Hypnosis & Memory) 1988 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - H – Miscellaneous 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - I – Miscellaneous 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Imagery Conference – San Diego 11/3- 6/88 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Invitations to speak, Reviews, Meetings 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - 11th International Congress of Hypnosis & Psychosomatic Medicine The Netherlands (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - University of Iowa Oct. 20-22 '88 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - XXIV International Congress of Psychology 8/28-9/2//88 Sydney, Australia (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - IJCEH Reviews 1988 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Indian Society for Clin. And Exper. Hypnosis (Pres. Dr. H. Jana) 1987-1989 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Jacobs, Marilyn Ph.D. Santa Monica, CA 1987 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - British J. of Experimental and Clinical Hypnosis. Brian J. Fellows, Editor 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Comment on: The Behavior of Organisms. J. Exper. Anal. of Behav. 1988 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Journal of Mental Imagery (Akhter Ahsen, Editor) (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Comment on Prof. Skepticism about Mulgiple Personality – J. Nerv. & Ment. Dis. E. Brody, Ed. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Stability of Hypnotizability Piccione, C., ERH, Zimbardo, P. Journal of Personality and Social Psychology 1988 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Journals (General) 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Journals for Sale (Alfred Jaeger) 1983-1988 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Psychological Reports (Carol & R. B. Ammons, Editors) 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Kihlstrom, John F. 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - L – Miscellaneous 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Laurence, J-R, & Perry, C. Hypnosis, Will & Memory: A psycho-Legal History. Guilford Press. 1988. (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Lindzey, Gardner 1988 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Leary, David E. 1988 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - M – Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Mc, Mac – Miscellaneous 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Mesmer Exhibition (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Murphy, Lois B. Ph.D. 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - N – Miscellaneous 1988 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - National Academy of Education 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Regional Roundtable – Stanford National Academy of Sciences 2-22-88 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - National Academy of Sciences 1988 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - National Science Foundation 1984-1988 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - O – Miscellaneous 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - P – Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Foreword: In Pachauri, A. R. A systematidc and chron. study…interr. & completed tasks in Psychology 1988 (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Popplestone, John A. (Director) Archives of History of APA Akron, Ohio 1988 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Psi Chi Initiation Banquet - Dominican College, San Rafael March 18, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Rains Dedication Ceremony: Hilgard Court November 1988 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Rosenzweig, Saul – Professor, Dept. of Psychology – Washington Univ. St. Louis, MO (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - S – Miscellaneous 1988 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Oshins (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Society for Clinical and Experimental Hypnosis – K. Bowers, Pres. 1988 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Society of Experimental Psychologists, Inc. 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Review in J Exp. Soc. Psychology re: Spanos, Flynn, Niles ms. Gruder, C. (Ed.) (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - SSPI (Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues) Jeffrey Z. Rubin, President (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Stanford University (Miscellaneous) 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Stanford University School of Education 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - T – Miscellaneous 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - U – Miscellaneous 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - Umemoto, Takao. Konan Women's U. Kyoto Japan 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - U. of Illinois Press ( R. Linnn, ED.) Intelligence – chapter (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - V – Miscellaneous 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Visitors 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - W- Miscellaneous 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - Foreword: Encounters w/ Great Psycholog. Wall & Thompson publ. 1988 (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - Foreword: to Waxman's Hartland's – Med. & Dent. Hypnosis (revis.) McMonagle Assoc. Ed. Bailliere Tindall, Ltd. (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - John Wiley & Sons, Inc. (Carol Beasley, Publisher) (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - WNET – Thirteen Film: "The Search for Mind" 1988 (Box 14, Folder 60)
  - Hypnosis Books Available (R. Wozniak, The Epistemologist) 1987 (Box 14, Folder 61)
  - X Y Z – Miscellaneous 1986-1988 (Box 14, Folder 62)
  - Zeig, Jeffrey K. Ph.D. The Milton H. Erickson Foundation, Inc. 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 63)
  - Articles Related to History of Psychology (Box 14, Folder 64)
  - APA Style Manual – Selections (Box 14, Folder 65)
  - B & B File- Hypnosis in Relief of Pain (Box 14, Folder 66)
  - B & B File: Bouquets and Brickbats (1986) (Box 14, Folder 67)
  - Computation Forms (Box 14, Folder 68)
  - Cooper-London data & analysis (Box 14, Folder 69)
  - Biographies Distinguished Psychologists (Box 14, Folder 70)
  - German Grammar (Box 14, Folder 71)
  - Graduate Student Directories (Box 14, Folder 72)
  - Deafness – Signal Detection (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Urhbrock, R.S. 9/80 Interview Transcript (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Wiley History Chart (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Hypnosis Book: Plans (Stanford University Press) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Inventory of Contents of Storage Cabinet Rm. 206 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Naruse Demonstration 4/4/62 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Planning Seminar – Notes (Sept. 1977) (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Psych 141 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Psychology 207. Contemporary Viewpoints in Psychology (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Twentieth Century Psychology in America: A History of …Recurrent Problems (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Institute for Advanced Study (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Duncan, Carl P.: Reviews of Books in History and Systems of Psychology (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Ford Foundation: Behavioral Science History (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Zimbardo (Jamie Newton) – Hypnosis Instructions (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Manuscripts, theses, papers by others A-B (Box 15, Folder 15-18)
  - Dessoir, M. (1888) Modernen Hypnotismus (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Erickson, M.H. (1958) Hypnotic Demonstration (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Chapter 12 of Arnold Gesell – Backup (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Hilgard, E.R. et al (1959) – The Distribution of Susceptibility to Hypnosis in a College Population (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Waterloo Group Form C (1988) (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Wyoming Group Form C (1982-1987) (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Manuscripts, theses, papers by others A-B (Box 15, Folder 25-44)
  - Manuscripts, theses, papers by others C - L (Box 16)
  - Manuscripts, theses, papers by others L – Z (Box 17)
  - Scales and Protocols [possibly restricted] (Box 18)
  - Forms, Protocols, and Profiles [possibly restricted] (Box 19)
  - Tests and scoring booklets, samples (Box 20)
  - Subjects consent forms (Box 20)
  - 2 binders of hypnosis research slides (Box 20)
  - Videorecordings
    - Neal Skin Rash treated by Ken Bowers, 1 video reel(s) (1 inch) (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Doretta Warden – bicycle regression, 1 video reel(s) (1 inch) (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - ERH address – SCSCH – "Research in Clinical Hypnosis." (1983), 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - ERH address – Idaho Psychological Association – (1981), 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Stanford Profile #1 Copy, 1 video reel(s) (1 inch) (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Stanford Profile #2 Copy, 1 video reel(s) (1 inch) (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Form C Demo, 1 video reel(s) (1 inch) (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - ERH: Hazards in Interrogation of Witnesses (Instructional Media), 1979; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Eyewitness LA – 2nd Segment, 1979; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic) (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Discussion with Hilgard, 2 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box 22)
  - Audiorecordings
    - B. Aronson: Time Distortions in hypnosis: Implications or mental disorders – Seminar at Stanford University, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Dr. Erika Fromm: Hypnotic Age Regression Vol. 51, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Dr. Erika Fromm: Screen Visualization Vol. 52, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - The Great Barber-Orne Debate, 1969 Nov; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Harvard Group Scale – Form B – April 1967, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Hoskovec and Cooper – Sleep Learning 1966, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Hoskovec and Cooper – Waking Learning 1966, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 21, Folder 16)